[Music]
i remember reading a book miss rumpus
when i was a child about a woman who
went about throwing lupine seeds on the
ground where she went and how eventually
she cultivated a heavenly world of
abundant flower fields
this trail behind my home reminds me of
her story and how the beauty of her soul
lived on and the legacy she left in
nature
it makes me want to pursue my passions
knowing that if i am true to myself and
find a way to do my small part in making
the world a better place then my legacy
will stand the test of time
people might not remember my name but i
can still be part of something beautiful
nonetheless
[Music]
so
it is so quiet right now
even the wind is um
blowing just so softly
i know that some of you have asked
before if i ever feel nervous out in the
wilderness or in the forest and
i i would say that i i don't i do carry
with me bear spray and you know just
everything for just basic safety you
know in the small chance that i would
have to be prepared for an unexpected
situation but for the most part i just
feel so peaceful out here it feels like
home you know it feels like you belong
here
and that this is a place
you know where
you come to heal and you come to think
and you
come to encounter yourself you are
surrounded by life and at the same time
you are still left in a way in your own
company from the perspective of not
having other humans around
and
that is powerful i think because
so many
things that you often think about when
you're around other people
feel very different when you're by
yourself
and
i think especially in terms of
how your awareness of your external self
so much of that depends on the
perception of other people
and when you're by yourself
you can really encounter
the truth of how you feel about yourself
because no one is here to
see you or judge anything you know
you're just in your own company and you
have to be very honest with yourself
how do i feel
about
me
what is it like to just exist
with myself
for this time that i'm out here it
really helps separate
what
the influence of other people have over
how you think and you feel
and the influence you have over how you
think and you feel
and sometimes it can be a wonderful
learning experience because you get to
this point that you
realize there's certain
negative thought patterns or feelings
that you want to work on and you want to
be free of
because you don't want to have to be in
your own company and be fearful or
uncomfortable isn't that the goal you
know when it comes to confidence and
self-love is to be 100 comfortable in
your own skin but also i think much more
important than that is to be comfortable
in the presence of your own
consciousness
of the thoughts and the feelings and the
words that you tell yourself
it's powerful it's very possible that
while i'm recording this all you're
going to hear are the birds because they
have suddenly
started singing so loudly
however i have to say that as i have
gone on a journey to
become my best friend it is really
interesting to be out here by myself
and realize instead of being
uncomfortable
only existing with myself you are in
fact so peaceful and it forces you to be
honest with yourself are you surrounding
yourself with people that influence you
in positive
ways in
perhaps challenging you to be a better
person but also respecting and embracing
who you are or do the people in your
life affect you very differently
and is there anything you can do about
that is there perhaps anything that you
can put into your life that will
help you ground yourself
throughout my life i have struggled to
know who i am what my opinions are
and to be assertive with what i want and
what i think instead of just defaulting
to the most confident person in the room
or
you know anyone that i see as superior
to me so yes those are my thoughts while
sitting outdoors
in a flower field it's just starting to
drizzle so i think i'm going to head
home
i went down a very steep
hill to uh get my bike down here so it's
going to take quite a bit of effort to
uh get it back up so
we'll see if i succeed
oh my foot's asleep ah
so
[Music]
oh
i think that if you seek out these quiet
places with intention you can use it as
an opportunity to really ask yourself
if no one is watching no one judging if
the only words spoken were the ones in
your own mind
how would you feel about yourself
i think a lot of insight can come from
that sort of exercise
at a point many years ago doing that
made me realize i was in a relationship
that was actively destroying my
self-esteem and that i only felt like
myself when i was away from them
and now sometimes when i go out and
spend time alone i still realize that i
have some lasting effects of that era
that i've been ignoring and need to work
on
so even now that i feel like i'm in a
good place in my life i'm still learning
something from my intentional walks
alone
i certainly think in terms of your
physical beauty and confidence it's
interesting how much of that is based
off of what we think other people see
and perhaps can get a taste of that
freedom of having a healthier
relationship with your external self
i think it's so important not to let
other people dictate any aspect of who
you are
[Music]
so
i did want to briefly uh give you a
little update on our households
it is a little bit sad it is related to
losing a pet i did lose my dear sweet
bunny this week mr darcy
he entered the winter years of his life
a long time ago
he's actually been with me for most of
my adult life
so
even though he's been having some health
problems and he's very old and we knew
this day was coming
soon
it still has been really hard
so yes he has been such a big part of my
life for so long we have loved him so
much and he has been a big part of this
channel too i still wanted of course to
make an uplifting video in a celebration
of his life
the other day we buried him
in the garden
under some wild flowers and it was
really
hard and really special
and we put a little rabbit figurine
there and actually right after i
buried him i noticed that there were
some
lily of the valley growing right next to
his little grave and
it was really sweet because i hadn't
noticed those flowers before they had
just popped up and i actually
painted those flowers on the entryway
of my house on the door
and so in a funny way it kind of feels
like he's
still with us watching over the house
and and it's a really it was really
comforting to see those flowers right
next to where he is resting now so i
just wanted to let you all know and
i do not mean for this little message to
be a real downer because it's also
a celebration of everything he's given
me and also
to this channel he's been such a big
part of it for so long i think perhaps
one of the main reasons i'm sharing this
is that i want all of you to
tell someone you love them or give them
a big hug or connect with someone you've
been meaning to connect with because we
don't know how long we have and i think
it's so important to do those things and
have those special moments sooner rather
than later so
anyway
sending you all my love
i will see you soon goodbye
you